JESSE WHITEHEAD

PROFILE

Web developer from northeast Kansas who enjoys being challenged in creating meaningful solutions that enhance people's daily lives. Offering 13 years of professional experience in problem-solving and customer satisfaction to create solutions for many scenarios, as well as a well-developed skill set in web development honed through coursework and numerous projects.

CONTACT

Address

1738 SW Hidden Valley Dr. Topeka, KS 66615

Phone

785.383.5374

E-mail

hello@jessewhitehead.com

Portfolio

www.jessewhitehead.com

GitHub

github.com/jessbob

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jesse-whitehead

SKILLS

HTML React
CSS Angular
JavaScript Vue

Nodejs Cloud Services
GitHub Mobile Development

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Frontend Development | Sept. 2019-Oct. 2019

- HTML
- CSS

JavaScript:

myFlix, course project, CareerFoundry | Oct. 2019-Nov. 2019

- Full-stack web app to provide users with information on movies, genres, and directors
- Developed with the MERN stack and Bootstrap

ToDo, course project, CareerFoundry | Nov. 2019

- Web app for making and updating list
- Created with Vue.js and styled with material design

Amazon Web Services:

Meet Up, course project, CareerFoundry | Dec. 2019-Jan. 2020

- Progressive web app that allows users to find meetups worldwide
- Created with React
- Utilizes AWS Lambda and OAuth to obtain authorization for the Meetup API

Serverless Contact Form, My Portfolio | Feb. 2020

- Allows users to easily contact me from a form on my portfolio
- Developed using AWS Lambda and Simple Email Service to handle the backend of my form and email me the user's message

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Spectacle: Optical Director & Digital Solutions Specialist | Aug. 2006–Sept. 2019

- Created a lab management database to organize and access every detail of current and past eyewear orders
- Implemented a lab management component to accommodate our eyewear orders when we had to upgrade our EHR system
- eyewear orders when we had to upgrade our EHR system
 Created marketing materials: fliers, brochures, and social media promotions
- Enhanced lab operations to maximize daily production
- Worked with suppliers to get the best frames and lenses at the best cost
- Managed retail optical operations to maximize patient care and revenue
- Trained optical staff on the technical aspects of frames and lenses

Hawkins Optical: Lab Technician | Nov. 2001–Aug. 2006

- Manufactured eyeglass lenses
- Machine repair and maintenance

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry | 2019 - 2020

- Intro to Frontend Development
- Full-Stack Immersion

Kaw Area Technical School | Sept. 2000 – May 2002

- Technical degree in Computer Science
- Focused on computer repair and entry-level networking
- Nominated to teach a web development course in 2002

Rossville High School | Aug 1997 - May 2001